smart gems are all the rage right now
and guess what I've got another one
ready to review for y'all speedience is
one of the newer smart gyms on the
market and it's coming for that number
one spot it has resistance built into it
there's hundreds of workouts for you to
do and the footprint is relatively small
I've been using mine for a few weeks and
I'm pretty pumped to share my experience
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time
I've got the speedience smart gym behind
me in this video I'm going to tell you
everything you need to know about this
smart gym from the price and the
features and of course the pros and cons
and who should or maybe should not
purchase one of these but before I get
going with all that we've reviewed a ton
of smart gyms on barbin.com so you know
what you should do you should go ahead
and search barbin best smart gyms and
you can find out for yourself which ones
that we like the best
[Music]
foreign
s well first and foremost I want to go
ahead and send a special thank you to
everybody over at expedience for not
making me assemble all this together on
my own so aside from the weight bench
I'm sitting on and the rowing
behind me everything was put together
and that's super nice it has a
relatively small footprint but the
platform underneath me right now
actually folds up it's going to expose a
set of wheels and you know it's going to
cut down even more on that footprint
make it really easy for you to move it
around your personal space and stash it
in a corner of the room if you choose to
do so it's essentially a functional
trainer so it's you know gonna be a
really nice option for anybody who's
super tight on space and I love using
cable machines at the gym I think it's a
great tool for anybody to use and these
feel really smooth in my opinion
especially when you're doing some tricep
push Downs or some chest flies you know
there's a lot of exercises that I could
name off but those really stick out to
me the most since this is in fact
digital weight you know it's all done
electromagnet genetically their smart
accessories are going to allow you to
turn the weight on and off with a simple
click of a button so you know once you
get set in position you're ready to
start your lift click the button and the
weight's going to turn on you're good to
go but if you're struggling with
something you can simply press the
button again it's going to turn off and
you can put it back in the starting
position and you're good to go there's
220 pounds of total resistance so each
cable has 110 pounds itself that's going
to be a lot of weight for a lot of
people watching right now and your
weight is going to be set automatically
for each individual exercise so once you
set up your original profile you have to
complete a strength assessment and after
that you're not gonna have to worry
about you know how much weight should I
be doing for a bicep curl or those
tricep push Downs you know it's going to
be done automatically but you can always
you know increase that weight if you
choose to do so there's also tons of
workouts for you to choose from there's
programs you can follow at weeks at a
time and you can also do a free lift if
you choose to do so where you can
literally do any exercise that you want
to do there's also different forms of
resistance such as chains where it
literally feels like you have chains on
a barbell for example there's also a
Centric modes where you know during The
Eccentric part of your lift it's going
to get harder on you to move that weight
now what about those potential issues
you might run into with speedience well
let's talk about the money first and
foremost so the basic package with
speedience is right around twenty seven
hundred dollars or so but that's not
including the Bluetooth accessories
which I personally think pretty
essential with a piece of equipment like
this so once you add those on it's gonna
be an extra 400 or so essentially at the
end of the day you're going to be
spending over three grand on this
product right here and you know if you
have a lot of space if you have you know
a garage or even just a room you can use
to build your own gym you know you might
be better off finding you know some
traditional equipment because you can
fill out that whole space for that much
money maybe even less than three
thousand dollars this is a great tool
for building strength but you know those
Elite power lifters out there 220 pounds
of weight might not be enough for you it
did feel like the cables operate on a
one-to-one ratio meaning you know if you
have 100 pounds on one of the cables you
got to have 100 pounds of force to move
that weight but you know that might not
be enough for some people and I know I
talked about how the cables feel really
smooth when doing some chest flies or
tricep push downs but I do have to say
it did feel a little bit weird when I
was bench pressing and squatting you
know it's definitely just because of the
cables it can be a little unstable at
times and that's just kind of something
that you have to learn to deal with the
Monitor and the framework of Speedy ants
are actually pretty much even and that's
a little bit of a cause for concern for
me and I'm sure for some of y'all as
well there's been a couple times where
I'm doing a workout with the barbell you
know I finished my set and the cable is
actually kind of you know guide the
barbell back to its starting position
and I'm afraid the apartment is going to
slide out of my hands and smack that
monitor and actually crack it so
definitely want to be careful when
you're doing that and the workouts are
guided but not in the same way as some
other smart gyms are so there's a
definitely a voiceover when you're
working out but kind of sounds like a
robot it's not you know an actual person
talking to you so that could be a little
bit you know weird for some people to
get used to it first but you can always
turn down that volume if you need to and
each workout does in fact have a video
of somebody performing the exercise
saying that could counteract the lack of
an actual person sitting there talking
to you there's also not any feedback
whenever you're doing an exercise and
let's say you know you have improper
form during that specific movement now
on their website it says that you know
they offer that but I personally haven't
found that I've purposely done some
movements the wrong way not extended my
arms fully and it still counts the rep
so you know that's a little something
you're going to have to get used to and
just really focus yourself you know on
finding that proper form switching
attachments can be a little bit
difficult at times now it's an easy
process but you know each individual
attachment slides into a little ball
right here on the cable machine and you
know there's been a couple times where
I've had that ball pulled away from the
cable and as I pull the attachment out
that ball shoots back and it pinched my
finger a couple times so you definitely
definitely want to be careful when
you're doing that I think the rowing
machine is a great idea you know this
rowing bench is pretty cool it's pretty
unique but I gotta say I've had some
trouble personally with keeping my feet
strapped in so you might be better off
doing this Barefoot I you know might
have better success than I've had but
just overall on my feet have had a hard
time staying locked in and since you
absolutely need Wi-Fi to access all of
the workouts you definitely want to make
sure you're pretty close to your router
or that you just have you know good
Wi-Fi signal in general because in the
beginning you know when you first select
a workout you have to download it and my
initial setup it took a pretty good
amount of time for that video to
download
[Applause]
so let's talk about the money now in a
little further detail you know once
again the basic package expedience
without the smart accessories without
the rowing bench that's going to be
right around twenty seven hundred
dollars once you tack on your shipping
that's another 400 or so that right
there you're already over three grand
now personally I definitely think this
piece of equipment is designed to be
used with the smart accessories so I
would suggest snagging those smart
accessories that's going to be another
400 or so and let's say you want that
rowing bench you know it's also another
400 or so so you know essentially you're
gonna be spending around four grand on
this piece of equipment and you know
don't get me wrong that's a lot of money
I don't think that's any type of secret
four thousand dollars one piece of
equipment that's a lot of money but
let's say you don't need more than 220
pounds of total resistance let's say you
don't have a ton of space for you to
work with I think it's probably gonna be
a pretty good option for you maybe even
your best option and and you probably
won't need any other piece of equipment
since you can work out your entire body
with just your speed units as far as
financing your purchase goes expedience
is going to allow you to use either
klarna or pay later from PayPal so you
know just to find out which one is best
for you personally I suggest checking
out both of those payments and seeing
what you'll be paying each month another
really cool thing is that for the rest
of 2022 there's actually no subscription
fee that you have to pay but in 2023 you
can expect to pay around 30 bucks or so
just to gain access to the available
workouts but the cool thing is you can
actually have up to five individual
profiles on your account so you could
technically split all of this you know
five different ways if you have the
means to do so
foreign
[Music]
that's going to be determined based off
of which package you decide to purchase
so let's say you go with the basic
package well that's only going to come
with the weight bench I'm sitting on
their version of a barbell and two
handles that can go onto the pulleys for
you to work out with now once again none
of those are the smart accessories and I
definitely think it's worth purchasing
those because that's how this piece of
equipment was designed to be used so
that smart accessories package is still
going to include the weight bench and
the barbell but you're also going to get
a smart clamp to go on your barbell as
well as the nylon rope attachment you're
going to get two smart handles two ankle
cuffs two ski handle attachments and
you're also going to get a pair of hooks
for you to store your barbell on in
between your sets now it's also worth
mentioning that if you want to grab the
rowing bench as well it's also going to
come with its own specific barbell for
your rowing now these barbells
definitely feel different you know the
rowing bar is a lot lighter the the
knurling is pretty passive but I gotta
say I was pretty impressed with their
barbell that you're gonna be using for
bench pressing and squatting the
knurling on it is actually pretty grippy
in my opinion and it's not too light
where it feels like you're not actually
you know bench pressing or squatting
okay so similar to the other smart gems
out there speedyans has tons of workouts
for you to do by the hundreds and that's
a growing list as we speak now unlike
some other smart gems though there's no
live classes for you to join at this
moment in time but I would imagine
that's going to be added in the not too
distant future I wouldn't let that steer
you away from speedy and so because once
again there's hundreds of workouts for
you to do and you can filter everything
based off of which part of the body you
want to focus on or maybe even Which
movement you want to do such as a back
squat for example plus everything is
broken down into three different
categories beginner intermediate and
advanced you know that way you're not
getting in over your head with a workout
I was a bit surprised there wasn't any
type of form feedback during your
workouts now on the FAQ section on the
speed against website it says they offer
that but you know maybe maybe it's you
know operator error maybe my form's too
perfect I'm just kidding we all we all
mess up sometimes times but you know I
purposely did some exercises wrong just
to see if there's any type of prompt
saying or any type of voice saying you
know like extend your arm fully or you
know fill in the blank and I personally
have not found that to be during any
type of my workout experience so I'm
sure there's a lot of people out there
that would really enjoy to have that
because a lot of people who are going to
be interested in this product are
probably pretty new to Fitness I think
the program section is a really awesome
tool for people to use this is
essentially a multi-week strength
program and all your weeks are going to
be split up for you but you can also
create your own custom workout program
and that's pretty awesome in my opinion
you know you can go ahead and select
which exercises that you want to do and
go ahead and toss them into one program
and it's always going to be saved for
you also really enjoy the free lift you
know you can just select any attachment
you want to do and just start doing any
movement that you find necessary
[Music]
when it comes to the build Speedy
ensuses 304 steel for the framework and
it has a nice black powder coat finish
on it the only color that you have to
choose from just wanted to go ahead and
mention that obviously though the
monitor it's touch screen and it's made
from glass so like I said earlier you
definitely want to be careful whenever
you're returning your attachments to the
starting position especially that
barbell you know I'm afraid personally
it's going to smack against it one day
and it's going to be cracked and I have
to replace that monitor it weighs a
hefty 190 pounds so you know you might
think it's really hard to move around
but thankfully the platform that I'm
sitting on right now you know it
actually folds up so it's going to
expose a set of wheels and trust me it
makes it super easy to move around your
personal space unless of course you know
you're working out in a room that has
carpet that's probably going to be a
little bit difficult for you in terms of
the footprint you know expedience is
going to make the most of your available
space so about six feet tall a little
over two and a half feet wide or so and
when the platform is unfolded it's
around four feet from front to back now
cool thing is when you do fold the
platform up it only sticks out about a
foot or so so you know you can easily
store it in the corner of your room and
you know make the most of your available
space
[Music]
okay so in terms of features you do have
a 21 and a half inch 1080p touchscreen
monitor it's gonna be really nice you
know you can easily browse through all
the available workouts but something I
think is really cool about it that it
actually rotates all the way down so
let's say you know you're doing a bench
press for example and you don't really
want to count all your reps in your head
you can rotate that monitor down as
you're laying down and you'll be able to
track everything right there on the
screen you have two 10 watt speakers on
the back of the speed ends and each
cable here actually has a max weight
resistance of 110 pounds with that
accuracy being down to around two pounds
or so now the Bluetooth capabilities are
pretty limited
um you know I haven't been able to
connect my phone to it I haven't had any
success doing that I wanted to see if I
was able to you know select a class from
my phone and hit pull up on the actual
Monitor and it I wasn't able to do that
so for me it seems as if the only
Bluetooth capabilities are actually for
your smart accessories and I'll explain
to you here in a minute on how to
actually connect all those smart
accessories to your expedience there is
no camera and there's also no 3D sensors
with speedience so there's really no
personal training you know feeling when
it comes to working out with it and you
know that could be you know a little bit
of a cause for concern for some people
because like I said earlier you know a
lot of people who are interested in a
product like this relatively new to
working out and they want to make sure
they're doing everything the proper way
so your best bet is to just follow along
with that guided video you know with
each person you know demonstrating the
specific exercise while you're working
out expedience does also offer a
companion app and it might not be as
extensive as some other companies offer
with their companion apps but it's still
a great way for you to track all your
stats you know like calories burned
total volume lifted you know duration of
your workouts and this is daily weekly
monthly yearly and all time so that's
pretty cool it's also a really nice way
to browse all the avail elbow workouts
and as you select them you're going to
see a detailed description on you know
the specific workout and the muscles
worked and you know so on and so forth
but once again you know you can't stream
any workout from the app that might
change in the future but as of right now
today you can't do that but I do think
it's really cool how you can create your
own custom programs from the app and
save it that way you know it's going to
be tied in directly to your speedience
it's going to pop up in your available
programs for you to select from you can
also do the same thing with the workouts
too if there's one you want to do you
want you really like it you can save it
and it'll pop up on your speedience and
you can do it the next time you decide
to work out
all right so let's go and do a quick
walk around with speedience I want to
talk about the framework first and
foremost you know once again this is
made from 304 steel it's got a nice
powder coat finish on it 304 steel is
one of the most commonly used forms of
Steel pretty much in the world so this
is pretty nice quality right here it
does wobble a little bit when it's
folded up but when this platform is
unfolded it's pretty stable I don't see
why it would fall over on you now when
it's folded up you do have your wheels
exposed right here which is really
helpful as you go to store it you know
and as you can see it's pretty thin so
you can easily you know stash it in the
corner of a room and you're good to go
now to unfold it there's a button right
here on the side just simply click it
it's going to unlock it this is going to
come right down for you I'd use this
little raised up almost like a handle
right here so you don't squish your
fingers
and then you have these little guys
right here you want to cure these down
tightly fasten them and then this isn't
going to move on you whatsoever now the
power switch is located on the back
mine's obviously already on but just
simply you know flip the switch turn it
on or off you have two 10 watt speakers
on the back of the monitor right here
remember this is touch screen which is
really cool but it also rotates down
which is really helpful and as you're
going to do a bench press you can look
up and you can track all your reps and
your range of motion and everything like
that which is really cool now
once you get everything pulled up right
here you have a bunch of recommended
workouts for you and they're also broken
down specifically by strength or shaping
and even specific Sports such as frisbee
CrossFit and even golf which is pretty
cool now
click on workout you know once again
there's recommended ones strength fat
loss sport specific you know really
whatever you want to do it's right here
which is pretty cool now let's go ahead
and find one for us to click on right
here I've already downloaded this one so
it's going to pull right up but if you
do one for the very first time it might
take you a minute or so to download this
workout now as you click on it you know
it's going to show you your target
muscles you know this one's back tries
and abs combined so it's going to
highlight all those areas right there
and if you scroll down it's going to
show you you know how everything is
broken apart how many reps and sets
you're going to do for each individual
exercise which is pretty nice
now if we go back to the home screen you
have a template right here you can
create your own custom workout just
click plus up here on the top click
right here on that plus you can add your
own movement you can break it's all
broken down by muscle grouping as well
so click on hamstrings there's all these
different hamstring exercises and
workouts for you to do same thing goes
for your quads and your rear delts so on
and so forth all the way down the line
and you can just save it it's always
going to be right here you can name it
you know whatever you want to name it
it's always going to be there for you
now let's keep going down the line right
here on this home page free lift is
probably my favorite option here with
expedience just simply select your
weight mode I mean you can do standard
chains it feels like there's chains with
your weight there's an eccentric you
know it's going to be more difficult
during The Eccentric portion of your
movement and this is just really nice
you know it's going to show you your
weight on each side right here if you
were doing a barbell you're over
compensating on one side it's going to
show you and over here on the right it's
going to show your range of motion and
just you know make sure you're getting
that full range now I'm just going to
keep on going down the line right here
programs are right here it's all split
up there's 14 right now but that's you
know it's a growing list there's going
to be more put on here as well as the
overall actual workouts that are on here
so it's broken down two weeks three
weeks four weeks five weeks you know if
you click on one it's basically
internet's a little shoddy right here in
the garage okay so here we go now it's
gonna break everything down you know
your first week second week you know so
on and so forth you know two days on one
day off two days on and the weekend off
so that's pretty nice I'm just going to
show you you know everything to do and
you can follow along pretty easily you
can also break everything down by
movement so if you want to do some
upright barbell rows barbell back squat
you know really whatever it's all right
here
and you know it's going to show you
which attachments you're gonna need so
you know this side seated biceps curl
you know you're gonna need the weight
bench and you're going to need these
handles right here to do that workout
now let's go ahead and transition over
to the accessories now you know this is
the Smart handle you have a button on
either side right here so you can turn
the weight on or off this button is also
going to be used to connect them to the
Bluetooth so
pull this little guy up right here click
on bluetooth if you hold down the button
right here
it's going to pop up mine's already been
connected you hear that nice little
noise right there it's going to pop up
showing that your handle is connected
now this feels pretty good in my hands
it feels pretty sturdy honestly it's got
a it's a rubber grip right here you know
be nice there was some knurling right
here but honestly like it it's totally
fine now to
take this attachment out there's a
button right here you just simply press
it it's going to unlock for you and the
same goes putting it back in just press
and hold and you're good to go now I
will not would not recommend
you having this little ball right here
this far away from the top of the cable
whenever you go to take your attachments
out because that's going to shoot up in
there like I said there's been a couple
times where I've pinched my fingers now
this rope attachment pretty much your
standard nylon rope you're gonna find
pretty much anywhere at a gym online on
Amazon you know wherever it's pretty
standard now I got my other attachments
right here on the weight bench and I
would really prefer if you would just
you know ignore the fact that I you know
sliced open my weight bench right here
be careful if you're using a box cutter
when you unbox everything because it's
right on top and I put a nice cut down
the middle of it okay anyways so these
are your ski handles right here they're
plastic but this is a really cool little
workout feature that you have these are
your hooks they're gonna I'll show you
where they go in just a second but it's
going to be used for your two barbells
right here I really like this barbell
you know a lot of times these smart gyms
they're making their barbells be pretty
light and I don't know the exact weight
for this one but it feels pretty sturdy
and it feels pretty pretty heavy and
honestly I'm I was pretty surprised with
the knurling right here I think that's
honestly pretty nice it's about as nice
as you could ask for it to be now you do
have this clamp right here and this is
going to operate the same way as the
buttons on the smart handles you just
press that button in the middle it's
going to turn the weight on or off you
know whenever you need it to be turned
on or off I would like that button to be
a little bigger though there's a couple
times I accidentally pressed you know
the plus sign when I was you know burnt
out for my workout and I wanted to stop
and accidentally added more weight and
that's really not that fun
now I will say
this is designed you know on purpose
this is for rowing and this is a really
light bar I mean you could hold it with
just a couple fingers right here if you
could balance it the knurling is a
little underwhelming I guess you could
say but that's you know on purpose
because you don't really need I guess
you know your rowing bar to be super
nerdled you do also have a couple ankle
cuffs right here
these are pretty standard you know but
in terms of in terms of ankle cuffs
she's going to go around your foot and
you can do glute Kickbacks you can do a
bunch of different things with these
right here now let's go and slide over
to the rowing bench here I'll go ahead
and bring this down for y'all
this is pretty standard as well
only problem I had with it though is
that my feet wouldn't really stay in you
know where they're supposed to stay
these straps
didn't really provide enough pressure
maybe I didn't position him the right
way so I would probably recommend doing
this Barefoot if you plan on doing the
rowing workouts this seat right here is
going to slide up and down which is
pretty cool you know that's really just
pretty standard though at the same time
now when you're using this same goes for
the weight bench as well you know you
just slide this right up here and it's
going to fit nicely and just allow you
to really get close to these cables and
use them the right way now
let's talk about the app okay so once
again you can't stream any of these
classes you know even yoga or stretching
you can't stream anything from your
phone but still a nice way to select and
you know go through all the workouts and
just really learn about them
individually and you can save them for
later you can also do all your
customization stuff right here as well
you know it creates your own templates
if you go to profile you know that's
where you're going to find your body
stats your strength assessment scores
stuff like that you can click on you
know my workout you can set a Target
Target calories duration volume and
Target workout Minds build muscle you
can change that though if you ever want
to to Fitness or fat loss
now if you click on workout stats it's
going to show your weekly monthly yearly
and your total workout stats and it's
going to break everything down by a
graphic and everything as well right
there but you can also do that from the
actual monitor if you want to do so so
all you have to do is click on your name
click on my work all this stuff was just
on the app I just showed you it's all
going to pull up right here as well
which is pretty helpful one last thing
right here I got to show you guys how to
adjust the height of your pulleys so
just simply pull out on this knob
it's going to unlock and you can slide
it all the way down you can slide it all
the way up you know really whatever you
want to do but say you're wanting to do
you know some rows say you're wanting to
squat
just simply press down on this button
right here
and this is going to slide right out for
you and what you're going to do is
there's a little slide right here on
both sides and you just want to align
this up right here
slide it right in there
and there you go it's locked in and you
can do a bunch of different workers
workouts from this angle you know you
can do your bicep curls really whatever
you want to do and same goes putting it
back simply press that button slide it
out
bring it up and set it here but I'm not
gonna do that yet I forgot to show you
guys
Your Hooks right here so these hooks for
your barbells you just simply slide that
in right here
it's a great way to store your bar
whenever necessary but remember since
this Monitor and these the framework
right here pretty much on an even plane
you want to be careful you know with the
barbell with the handles really all of
it
you don't want to run the risk of
smacking up against your monitor and
cracking it because that's just no fun
okay so who should purchase the
speedience smart gym well I think this
is going to be a really solid product
for anybody who's tied on Space you know
really you're going to get the most out
of your available space since you know
it doesn't take up a whole lot of room
and you can fold it up you can easily
stash it in the corner of your room once
you're done working out while there's no
really type of instructor for all your
workouts you know if you're new to
Fitness still think you're going to
really like this product because there
are voiceovers on how to properly do the
exercise as well as guided videos for
each individual workout that you decide
to do and lastly anyone who wants a
workout program to follow but doesn't
really know how to create their own
program I think you're really going to
enjoy the fact that you have multiple
for you to choose from with speedience
[Music]
foreign
T want to purchase this smart gym well
let's talk about the weight resistance
first you know 220 pounds might be
plenty for the average weight lifter but
you know if you're somebody of elite
strength then that's probably not going
to be enough for you my friend so if
that's the case you know you're probably
gonna be better off with some
traditional weights and let's stick with
that you know if you feel a little bit
awkward when you're bench pressing or
squatting with speedience you know
there's really nothing you can do about
it and if that's something you can't
really become accustomed to or you know
something you can't really power through
then once again you're probably going to
be better off with some traditional
weights and lastly let's talk about the
money and you could potentially be
spending around four grand on just this
one piece of equipment that's a lot of
money you know if you have a good amount
of space if you have a garage you can
stash some gear in you know you can find
a lot of gear you can pretty much fill
out that entire garage for less than
four thousand dollars well that about
wraps up today's crash Course Review
over expedience I personally really like
this piece of equipment there's hundreds
of workouts for you to do there's a free
lift option for you there's a bunch of
workout programs for you to follow and
it's just an overall great way to stay
in shape remember though it is pretty
pricey and the squatting and benching is
going to feel pretty different than what
a lot of you are used to thanks for
hanging out with me everybody I hope
this video was really helpful and I was
able to answer any questions that you
may have about this product as always
stay posted for my next review but for
now in your free time head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
speedience just search bar band
expedience home gym review and you'll
find everything that I talked about here
today I'll see y'all next time
[Music]
foreign